Guide to the Building Trades Oral History Project OH.045
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Building Trades Oral History Project
1998-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
OH.045
3.5 Linear Feet
Building Trades Oral History Project (OH 045) consists of recordings of oral histories conducted by Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives staff between 1998 and 2002, and accompanying transcripts. The interview subjects are union members in the building and construction trades and labor officials.
Conditions Governing Access
Unless otherwise noted, materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Interviews conducted by Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives staff between 1998 and 2001. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1950.094 and 1978.015.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Scope and Contents
Building Trades Oral History Project (OH 045) consists of recordings of oral histories conducted by Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives staff between 1998 and 2002, and accompanying transcripts. The interview subjects are members of building and construction trade unions, including Metalic Lathers Union, Carpenters and Joiners, Sheetmetal Workers, International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Steamfitters, Building Trades Employers Association, General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen, Dockbuilders, and Bricklayers, among others. The collection also includes some interviews with labor officials, such as Former Deputy Commissioner of Labor Louis Levine.
- Adam, Eleanor, June 1, 2000; cuid14537 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14537A, cuid14537B)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 5A)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Duration: 63 minutes
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 5B)
    Duration: 36 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 5A-5B)
- Allen, Kenneth (Metalic Lathers Union, Local 46), December 27, 2001; cuid14452 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14452)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 28)
    Duration: 72 minutes
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alongi, Vincent (Carpenters and Joiners, Local 2090), October 24, 2000; cuid14453 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14453A)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 34A)
    Duration: 94 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 34A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Andrucki, George (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 28), December 2, 1998; cuid14454 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14454A, cuid14454B)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 33A)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 33B)
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 33A-33B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bartels, Robert (Steamfitters Local 638), December 18, 2001; cuid14455 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14455A)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 32A)
    Duration: 84 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 32A)
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 32A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Blain, William (International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 3), April 15, 1998; cuid14456 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14456A, cuid14456B)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 31A)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 31B)
    Duration: 56 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 31A-31B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bloom, April, July 11, 2000; cuid14538 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14538A, cuid14538B)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 1A)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 1B)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 1A-1B)
- Bombardiere, Mio (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 137), November 18, 1999; cuid14457 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14457A, cuid14457B)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 30A)
    Duration: 95 minutes
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 30B)
    Duration: 8 minutes, Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 30A-30B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Brennan, Vincent (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 21, 1998; cuid14458 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14458A)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 27A)
    Duration: 85 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 27A)
- Colbert, Neil (Tile, Marble and Terrazo, Local 7), June 10, 1999; cuid14459 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14459)
  - Original Recording (Box 6)
    Duration: 78 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette cuid14459)
    Custodial History
    As of February 2025, this item is missing.
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Coletti, Louis J. (Building Trades Employers Association), July 31, 2001; cuid14460 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14460A, cuid14460B)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 29A)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 29B)
    Duration: 28 minutes, Note: Side 2 is blank.
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 29A-29B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Collins, Paul (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 137), October 4, 1999; cuid14461 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14461A, cuid14461B)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 26A)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 26B)
    Duration: 61 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 26A-26B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Contello, Sal (Bricklayers, Local 1), June 12, 1998; cuid14462 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14462A)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 25A)
    Duration: 40 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 25A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Cush, Edward (Ironworkers, Local 361), March 21, 2001; cuid14463 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14463A, cuid14463B)
  - Original Recording -- Part One (Box 4, Audiocassette 24A)
  - Original Recording -- Part Two (Box 4, Audiocassette 24B)
    Duration: 67 minutes
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Daly, Martin (Carpenters District Council), October 29, 1998; cuid14464 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14464)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 23A)
    Duration: 47 minutes, Note: Side 2 is blank
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 23A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Doyle, Jack (Ironworkers, Local 40), January 15, 2002; cuid14465 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14465A, cuid14465B)
  - Original Recording -- Part One (Box 2, Audiocassette 6A)
    Durations: 94 minutes
  - Original Recording -- Part Two (Box 2, Audiocassette 6B)
    Durations: 40 minutes
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Forde, Michael (Carpenters District Council), March 20, 2002; cuid14466 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14466A)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 22A)
    Duration: 82 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 22A)
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 22A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Gerosa, Al (Cement League of Greater New York), October 1, 2001; cuid14467 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14467A, cuid14467B)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 21A)
    Duration: 64 minutes
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 21B)
    Duration: 60 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 21A-21B)
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 21A-21B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Glynn, Eugene (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 22, 1998; cuid14468 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14468A, cuid14468B)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 19A)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 19B)
    Duration: 30 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 19A-19B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Hill, Charlie (Tile, Marble and Terrazzo, Local 7), May 11, 1999; cuid14469 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14469A, cuid14469B)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 20A)
    Duration: 25 minutes
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 20B)
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 20A-20B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Hirsch, Sam (Painters District Council), May 7, 2001; cuid14470 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14470A, cuid14470B)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 17A)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 17B)
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 17A-17B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Hirsch, Sam (Painters District Council), June 7, 2001; cuid14540 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14540B)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 18A)
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Audiocassette 18B)
  - Access Copy (Box 4, Audiocassette 18A-18B)
- Holloway, Dennis (International Masonry Institute of Bricklayers and Allied Trades), June 25, 1998; cuid14471 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14471)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 16A)
    Duration: 62 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 16A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Humphrey, Thomas (Stone Derrickmen and Riggers, Local 197), October 12, 1999; cuid14472 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14472)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 15A)
    Duration: 93 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 15A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Kelly, John (Iron Workers, Local 40), November 14, 2001; cuid14473 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14473A, cuid14473B)
  - Original Recording -- Part One (Box 3, Audiocassette 12A)
    Duration: 57 minutes
  - Original Recording -- Part Two (Box 3, Audiocassette 12B)
    Duration: 87 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 12A-12B)
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 12A-12B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Kelly, William (Iron Workers, Local 197), November 12, 1999; cuid14474 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14474A, cuid14474B)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 11A)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 11B)
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 11A-11B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Kennedy, John (Building and Construction Trades Council of Nassau and Suffolk Counties), October 31, 2001; cuid14475 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14475A, cuid14475B)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 10A)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 10B)
    Duration: 37 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 10A-10B)
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 10A-10B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Lanzafame, Santo (Bricklayers, Local 1), November 18, 1998; cuid14476 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14476)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 39A)
    Duration: 50 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 39A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Ledwith, Robert (Metallic Lathers, Local 46), March 19, 2001; cuid14477 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14477A, cuid14477B)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 8A)
    Duration: 21 minutes, Note: Sound quality is poor.
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 8B)
    Duration: 94 minutes, Note: Sound quality is poor.
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 8A-8B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Ledwith, Robert (Metallic Lathers, Local 46), December 28, 2001; cuid14478
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 9A)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 9B)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 9C)
    As of February, 2025, this item is missing.
    Duration: 20 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 9A-9C)
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 9A-9C)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Levine, Louis (Former Deputy Commissioner of Labor), January 20, 1999; cuid14479 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14479A, cuid14479B)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 7A)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 7B)
    Duration: 12 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 7A-7B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Lusardi, Dennis (Ironworkers, Local 580), December 28, 2001; cuid14480 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14480)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 46A)
    Duration: 92 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 46A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Maiello, Gene (New York District of Carpenters), November 27, 2000; cuid14481 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14481A, cuid14481B)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 13A)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 13B)
    Duration: 19 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 13A-13B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Malloy, Edward (Building and Construction Trades Council), August 8, 2002; cuid14482 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14482)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 4A)
    Duration: 81 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 4A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Martin, Raymond (General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen), July 31, 2002; cuid14483 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14483A)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 2A)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 2B)
    Note: Tape B was not transferred.
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 2A-2B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 32)
- McGuire, Ray (Contractors Association of Greater New York), November 12, 2001; cuid14484 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14484A, cuid14484B)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 38A)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 38B)
    Duration: 28 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 38A-38B)
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 38A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Nicastri, Ronald (Tile, Marble and Terrazzo, Local 7), June 21, 1999; cuid14485 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14485A, cuid14485B)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 37A)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 37B)
    Duration: 41 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 37A-37B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 34)
- O'Brien, William (Painters District Council 9), November 13, 2001; cuid14486 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14486A, cuid14486B)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 36A)
  - Original Recording (Box 5, Audiocassette 36B)
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 36A-36B)
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 36A-36B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 35)
- O'Donnell, John (Association of Plumbing Contractors), October 26, 2001; cuid14487 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14487A, cuid14487B)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 14A)
  - Original Recording (Box 3, Audiocassette 14B)
  - Access Copy (Box 3, Audiocassette 14A)
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 35A-35B)
  - Access Copy (Box 5, Audiocassette 35A-35B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 36)
- O'Kane, Richard (Ironworkers, Local 361), March 9, 2001; cuid14488 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14488A, cuid14488B)
  - Original Recording -- Part One (Box 6, Audiocassette 45A)
    Duration: 94 minutes, Note: Volume fluctuates between interviewer and interviewee.
  - Original Recording -- Part Two (Box 6, Audiocassette 45B)
    Duration: 9 minutes, Note: Volume fluctuates between interviewer and interviewee.
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 45A-45B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Robinson, Guy, Aug 09, 2002; cuid14539 (Box Digitized Access Files, Cassette cuid14539A)
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 3A)
    Duration: 74 minutes
  - Original Recording (Box 2, Audiocassette 3B)
    Note: Tape B is a duplicate of tape A.
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 3A-3B)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 3A-3B)
  - Access Copy (Box 2, Audiocassette 3A-3B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Rothberg, William (Sheet Metal Industry Promotion Fund), November 20, 2000; cuid14489 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14489A, cuid14489B)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 43A)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 43B)
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 43A-43B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Rothberg, William (Sheet Metal Industry Promotion Fund), October 19, 2000; cuid14490 (Box Digitized Access Files, Cassette cuid14490A, cuid14490B)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 44A)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 44B)
    Duration: 11 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 44A-44B)
  - Transcript (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Simmons, Alan (Ironworkers District Council), January 19, 2001; cuid14491 (Box Digitized Access Files, Cassette cuid14491A, cuid14492B)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 42A)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 42B)
    Duration: 5 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 42A-42B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Thomassen, Peter (Dockbuilders, Local 1456), November 30, 1998; cuid14492 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14492A)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 41A)
    Duration: 70 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 41A)
  - Access Copy (Box 6, Audiocassette 41A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Torpey, John R. (Steamfitters, Local 638), January 12, 1999; cuid14493 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14493A, cuid14493B)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 40A)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 40B)
    Duration: 14 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 123, Cd 40A-40B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Ulrich, Werner (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 6, 1998; cuid14494 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14494A, cuid14494B)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 48A)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 48B)
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 48A-48B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Valegatos, Sandy (Painters District Council 9), January 10, 2001; cuid14495 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14495A, cuid14495B)
  - Original Recording (Box 6, Audiocassette 47A)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 47B)
    Duration: 29 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 47A-47B)
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 47A-47B)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Walsh, Edward J. (Ironworkers, Local 40), January 5, 2001; cuid14496 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14496A, cuid14496B, cuid14496C)
  - Original Recording -- Part One (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 49A)
  - Original Recording -- Part Two (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 49B)
  - Original Recording -- Part Three (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 49C)
    Duration: 10 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 49A-49C)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Walsh, Robert (Ironworkers, Local 40), August 24, 2001; cuid14497 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14497)
  - Original Recording -- Master (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 50A)
    Duration: 116 minutes
  - Original Recording -- Dub (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 50A)
    "high speed"
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 50A)
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 50A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Winbush, Zacharius (Bricklayers, Local 1), June 12, 1998; cuid14498 (Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14498A)
  - Original Recording (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 51A)
    Duration: 46 minutes
  - Access Copy (Box Shared Tamiment 098, Audiocassette 51A)
  - Transcript (Box 1, Folder 48)